Underlying the history of war, there is always a mysterious key
在戰爭史的背後 總是有一把神祕的鑰匙
that seduces man and stirs his desires.
引誘著人類，勾起人的慾望
Devil's key?
惡魔鑰匙？
It's the key to the game run by the devil.
這把鑰匙能啟動由惡魔管理的遊戲
If you win the game,
如果在遊戲中獲勝
you can take anything you want from the loser.
你就能獲得敗者的任何東西
Just like Maruko,
像丸子一樣
there will be others chosen by the key
這裡會有其他人被鑰匙選中
who will cross your path.
然後跟你對上
I will find you, and make you pay for killing my father.
我會找到你的 讓你為殺害我父親付出代價
Call me Senya.
叫我潛夜就行了
Who are you?
你是誰？
Does this answer your question?
這樣能回答你的問題嗎？
A man called Teruasa Oda has the same key.
有一個叫織田照朝的人 也擁有這樣的鑰匙
He is an experienced player.
他是個有經驗的玩家
You don't stand a chance against him.
你跟他玩遊戲沒有任何勝算
WEDNESDAY, OCTOBER 23RD
（10月23日星期三）
If you have the choice…
如果要選的話…
you should take on a beginner.
我建議你選一個新手
KEY OWNER YUKARI SHIKIBE - 18 YRS OLD
（式部紫，18歲）
Yukari!
小紫
Yukari! Yukari!
小紫…
-Yukari! -Thank you, everyone!
-小紫 -謝謝大家
Yukari!
小紫
Don't come near me!
不要過來
I'm not giving this key to anyone!
我不會把鑰匙交給任何人的
Sorry, out the way.
借過一下
You're the chairman of Miyanouchi Group.
你是宮之內集團的會長吧？
The lucky owner of a key, huh?
能成為鑰匙的主人真幸運啊
Who are you?
你是誰？
Teruasa! Come and try this.
照朝，快過來嚐嚐
Is it chocolate?
巧克力？
Wow, it's yummy.
真好吃
You like it!
太好了
Hey! He said it's yummy.
他說好吃
That's right,
這款巧克力
your mom designed that with the food department.
是你媽媽和我們食品部一起研發的
It's called "Mog chocolate."
它叫“莫格巧克力”
-Mog chocolate? -Yes.
-莫格巧克力？ -對
-Think it'll sell? -Dunno…
你覺得它會大賣嗎？
Looks a bit like bunny poop, so maybe not.
它長得像兔子的便便，所以可能不會
Don't be so cheeky!
你說這什麼話？
A highly valued opinion.
這可是寶貴的意見
Then can I join the company and figure out how to sell stuff?
那我能加入爸爸的公司 研究讓它暢銷的方法嗎？
What's this?
什麼？
You want to do what your dad does?
你想繼承爸爸的事業？
I wonder if I can.
不知道我有沒有辦法
I'm sure of it.
你一定可以的
If you keep working hard.
只要繼續努力就可以
you can do it, Teruasa.
加油，照朝
Do you promise?
我們約定好囉？
I'm sorry.
那個約定
I couldn't keep my promise.
我沒能履行，抱歉
TO TERUASA HAPPY 11TH BIRTHDAY
（祝照朝11歲生日快樂）
It's okay to cry if you need to.
想哭就哭吧，照朝
Mom will be sad if I cry.
我哭的話，媽媽會難過的
Where's the key?
鑰匙在哪裡？
I have no such thing.
我沒有這種東西
Dad!
爸爸
The man who killed you
殺害你的凶手
contacted me.
找上我了
This key
爸爸
has many secrets.
這把鑰匙的祕密
How much did you know?
你瞭解多少？
They want to invest?
他們想要投資？
Yes, okay.
好，好的
Of course, thank you very much!
當然，非常感謝
Score!
太好了
Good job, Ui!
太棒了，初
Are you going to tell Yuki?
把這個好消息告訴悠季吧？
You bet.
好啊
Hey, Yuki,
悠季
I had a call just now－ What?
我剛才在講電話…什麼？
What video?
什麼影片？
Yuki?
悠季？
Something bad's happened.
照朝君，不好了
It's the chairman of the Miyanouchi Group.
宮之內集團的會長出事了
Check the link I'm sending you now.
我現在就把連結傳給你
MESSAGE FROM YUKI MANABE
（來自真鍋悠季的訊息）
WATCH NOW! THE CHAIRMAN'S IN TROUBLE
（快看！會長出事了）
MAN THROWS MONEY FROM BRIDGE #MIYANOUCHI
（男子在橋上撒錢，#宮之內）
I, Yoshichika Miyanouchi…
我，宮之內義近…
CHAIRMAN MIYANOUCHI GOES MAD
（宮之內會長失去理智）
…hereby pledge to transfer…
…發誓要將…
MONEY-THROWING MAN IS THIS ASSET TRANSFER?
（撒錢男子，這是資產轉讓嗎？）
…all management rights of the Miyanouchi group
…宮之內集團的經營權全部轉交給
to Uesugi!
上杉先生
I'll call you back.
悠季，我晚點再打給妳
Is that Terurin?
是小照照嗎？
I guess you saw the video?
我猜你看到影片了吧？
What have you done to Miyanouchi?
你對宮之內先生做了什麼？
More questions?
你好愛問問題喔
I'll answer if you win the game.
你贏了遊戲後，我就告訴你
Where are you now?
你現在在哪裡？
Right now?
現在？
Somewhere I'm sure you've been before.
在一個你肯定來過的地方
Just chilling out in the seat your father used to sit in.
我正在你父親坐過的椅子上等著你
Why are you there?
你怎麼會在那裡？
Hurry along now.
趕快過來吧
I'm waiting.
我在等你
Teruasa!
照朝
Ui?
初
I saw the video.
我看到那個影片了
Did Uesugi have something to do with it?
這跟那個叫上杉的傢伙有關嗎？
I think so.
是的
I'm not letting you go alone.
我不會讓你一個人去的
Senya Uesugi is 27 years old.
上杉潛夜，今年27歲
He was arrested for gambling in 2017.
他在2017年因為賭博罪被捕
Numerous witnesses report seeing him at black market casinos.
在那之後 很多目擊者說在地下賭場見過他
Uesugi!
上杉
Using my smile to turn frowns upside down,
擁有讓人破涕為笑的微笑力量
I'm racing to the top of the idol world.
立志成為偶像界的第一名
My name is Yukari Shikibe!
我就是式部紫，綽號叫“小紫”
Right?
好耶
What?
怎麼會？
Don't tell me you haven't heard of Yukari?
難道你不認識小紫？
She's an idol!
她是偶像明星
I thought she'd cheer you up.
為了讓你高興一點
Even got her to wear her costume.
我硬是讓她穿上了表演服
Oh, yeah.
對了
By the way, she's got a devil's key too.
順便說一下，她也有惡魔鑰匙
Chairman Miyanouchi came after me,
我被宮之內會長盯上時
but Senya came to my rescue!
是潛夜君救了我
She liked me straightaway,
她立刻成了我的粉絲
so I let her off the hook.
所以我就替她解圍了
You see, women like a strong man.
女孩子就是喜歡強大的男人
-Right? -Right!
-對吧？ -對
Quieten down, little playboy.
閉嘴吧，渣男
If it means I can keep the key,
為了保住惡魔鑰匙
I'll flirt and smile all you want.
要我怎麼笑臉逢迎都可以
I wouldn't get mixed up in this if I were you.
勸妳不要捲入我們之間的事
Great advice!
真是好建議
Just like I thought,
和我想的一樣
you dragged your luggage along with you.
你這次又拖著包袱過來
Quit babbling.
少廢話
Uesugi, let's get to the point.
上杉，別說廢話了
Return the Miyanouchi Group.
把宮之內集團還給我
Meaning?
什麼意思？
Let's play the game.
和我玩遊戲吧
Terurin, you are so lovely.
小照照，你太可愛了
So, Senya Uesugi.
上杉潛夜
What do you want, and from whom?
你想從誰那裡得到什麼？
Obviously, my opponent is…
我的對手當然就是…
Terurin.
小照照
And what I want is
我想要的是
maybe his friend's life?
他朋友的命怎麼樣？
You can't!
不可以
Oh, sorry!
騙你的
I want everything he knows about the devil's keys.
我要他對惡魔鑰匙掌握的所有資訊
Accepted.
同意
Teruasa Oda,
織田照朝
there will be no tricks from you this time.
這次不准再耍花招
I want to know everything Senya Uesugi knows about the keys and Hoshin.
我要上杉潛夜 對惡魔鑰匙和崩心掌握的所有資訊
Fine, accepted.
可以，同意
I'm not done.
還有
I want you to return the company to Chairman Miyanouchi.
我要你把集團還給宮之內會長
Are you some kind of idiot?
你是傻子嗎？
Don't you want it for yourself?
難道你不想將集團據為己有？
Teruasa, you were supposed to take over the company.
照朝，你本來就應該接管集團的
I know.
我知道
But winning a company on a bet is ridiculous.
但拿集團當賭注是荒謬之舉
I've made up my mind!
好，我決定好了
If you lose, I want you to do three things for me.
如果你輸了 我要你按我的吩咐做三件事
Anything I like.
我說做什麼，你就做什麼
That spices things up.
有意思
Accepted.
同意
Now take your oaths.
那就宣誓吧
I will fight for my desires.
我會為我的欲望而戰
I will triumph for my desires.
我會為我的欲望奪勝
-I swear on the devil.
-我向惡魔宣誓
Oaths accepted.
我接受你們的宣誓
This time, the game is called…
這次的遊戲叫…
"Five One."
“五印一當”
The game uses 15 cards.
這個遊戲會用到15張牌
Diamonds, spades, hearts, and clubs.
方塊、黑桃、紅心和梅花
And this one is a devil card?
這個長角的是惡魔牌嗎？
There are three of each suit.
每個花色有三張牌
Fifteen cards in total.
一共15張牌
One of these cards…
其中一張牌會變成這樣…
It's turned totally black.
正面和背面都塗黑了？
You must guess the symbol on this card.
你們需要猜出這張黑牌的花色
This card is "Five One."
這就是“五印一當”的玩法
Each player is dealt three cards from the rest of the pack,
我會從剩下的牌裡 發三張牌給每個玩家
which will give you the information needed to start the game.
這將是你們的線索
By reasoning from these three cards,
根據這些線索
each player will take turns to guess the suit of the black card.
每個玩家輪流猜黑牌的花色 並給出答案
The first to get the correct symbol, gets one point.
先猜中花色的玩家得一分
The first with three points is the winner.
先得三分者獲勝
There are five types of card.
這些牌一共有五種花色
So the probability of guessing right is 20 percent.
所以首次猜中的機率是20%
As the game continues, the probability of guessing right goes up.
隨著遊戲的進行，猜中的機率會提高
One more thing.
還有一點
On the first turn only,
只有在每輪的第一回合
both players can reveal as many cards as they like from their hand.
兩個玩家都可以隨意決定 亮出幾張自己的牌
Of course, that means the opponent will be able to see the symbols.
當然，對手也能看到亮出的牌
But
不過
how is that useful?
這有什麼用？
If you show your cards
亮牌的玩家
you receive the same number of new cards.
可以得到相同數量的新牌
If you share information…
以向對手公開線索為代價…
NEW CARDS
（新牌）
You get new information all to yourself,
…獲得只有自己能看到的新線索
which makes it easier to figure out what the black card is.
這樣更容易猜出黑牌的花色
Let the game begin!
遊戲開始
In the first round,
在第一回合中
this is the card I need to guess.
這是我要猜的牌
FIVE ONE ROUND ONE
（五印一當，第一回合）
I have the devil power, Limited Perfect.
我有惡魔之力“有限完美”
No doubt this guy has some special ability too.
但這個傢伙肯定也擁有某種特殊能力
But what is it?
他的能力會是什麼呢？
And when will he use it?
他會在什麼時候使用呢？
The first player is Senya Uesugi.
先猜的人是上杉潛夜
Declare how many cards you want to reveal.
說出你要亮多少張牌
I'm not showing any cards.
我不打算亮牌
I already know the answer.
我已經知道答案了
The symbol on the card is…
這張牌的花色是…
a club.
梅花
Incorrect!
錯誤
Oh, what a shame!
真遺憾
That would have been such a killer bluff if I'd been right.
要是猜對的話 這招虛張聲勢就太厲害了
You've gotta be kidding me.
你開什麼玩笑？
Now clubs have been eliminated,
現在梅花被排除了
it leaves diamonds, spades, hearts, or the devil.
正確答案 只可能是方塊、黑桃、紅心或惡魔
A 25 percent chance of success.
猜中機率提高到了25%
But why didn't he show any cards?
但是那個傢伙為什麼不亮牌？
Is he bluffing to mess with my head?
他在故弄玄虛，好讓我摸不清頭緒？
Or he gained something useful from guessing straightaway.
還是說，他覺得直接猜答案更有利？
Oh, yeah.
對了
Since I'm calling you Terurin,
我都叫你小照照了
feel free to drop "Uesugi."
你也別叫我“上杉”啦
My first name will do.
叫我“潛夜”就行了
We're not friends.
我們不是朋友
Cold as ice!
好冷漠
I should have added another demand.
我在提出要求時應該加上一條
To force you to become my bestie.
強迫你當我的朋友
If he has three cards of the same suit in his hand,
如果他手上的三張牌是同一個花色
he's excluded the clubs, and the suit in his hand,
他排除了梅花，再排除他手上的花色
and his chance of success is 33 percent.
那麼猜中機率是33%
So it was better to keep his cards hidden.
所以亮牌對他來說沒有好處
Now I have a huge disadvantage.
現在我處於絕對的劣勢
At the very least, knowing his hand would have put us in the same position.
如果能知道他手上拿到什麼牌 我們至少能站在同一個起跑線上
Wait…
對了…
I have a heart and two diamonds.
我有一張紅心和兩張方塊
The symbol on the card is a club.
這張牌的花色是梅花
Incorrect.
錯誤
Clubs have been excluded.
梅花被排除了
If this guy has three of the same card,
如果那個傢伙的三張牌是同一個花色
then they must be devil cards, or spades.
這三張牌肯定就是惡魔或黑桃
If that's true…
這樣的話…
I'll show all three cards.
我亮三張牌
You receive three cards in return.
那麼我再發三張牌給你
A spade.
黑桃
That means that he must have
這表示他手上肯定拿的是
three devil cards.
三張惡魔牌
So there's no way the black card is a devil card.
所以黑牌的花色絕對不是惡魔
Two diamonds on the table
桌上有兩張方塊
and one in my hand, so it can't be diamonds either.
還有一張在我手上 所以答案也不可能是方塊
So the answer is hearts or spades.
因此答案不是紅心就是黑桃
Fifty percent chance of success.
猜中機率為50%
Teruasa Oda, take your guess.
織田照朝，說出你的答案
My answer is spades.
我的答案是黑桃
Incorrect.
錯誤
Shit, you were wrong.
可惡，猜錯了
Don't worry.
現在還不需要擔心
I've reached the right answer.
我已經推出了正確答案
It must be hearts.
答案一定是紅心
Second turn. Senya Uesugi, you're next.
第二輪，上杉潛夜，換你猜
This time you can't show any cards.
這一輪不能亮牌了
Take your guess.
說出你的答案
Okay! I'm going for…
好，我的答案是…
hearts.
紅心
Just kidding.
是錯誤的
It's a devil card.
是惡魔才對
It's not a heart?
不是紅心？
Correct! One point to Senya Uesugi.
正確，上杉潛夜得一分
Gotcha!
好耶
A devil card?
惡魔？
When you saw I didn't show any cards,
當你看到我不亮牌時
you made a rookie error, assuming I had three of the same card.
你就猜測我的三張牌是同一個花色
Just because I said clubs…
因為我一開始說的答案是梅花
a club.
梅花
You jumped to the conclusion I didn't have a club in my hand.
於是你得出結論，我手上沒有梅花
But hold on.
但是…
That's too bad.
真遺憾啊
After that, you went and showed me three cards,
我猜小照照你一定會亮出三張牌
just like I knew you would.
結果確實如我所料
You gave away one heart and two diamonds.
你亮出了一張紅心和兩張方塊
So if you assumed I had three of the same card,
所以如果你認定 我的三張牌是同一個花色
you'd think the black card was a devil or spade.
你會猜測黑牌不是惡魔就是黑桃
After you got three new cards,
然後你得到了三張新牌
you went for spades.
你猜答案是黑桃
Incorrect!
錯誤
Wonderful, truly wonderful.
精彩，真的太精彩了
You concluded I must have three devil cards.
你斷定我一定拿著三張惡魔牌
Meaning,
也就是說
the three new cards you got didn't include a devil card.
重新發給你的三張牌裡沒有惡魔牌
One heart on the table,
桌上有一張紅心
and two in my hand.
我手上有兩張紅心
Spades was wrong, clubs was wrong. Leaving…
黑桃不正確 梅花不正確，剩下的就是…
A diamond or devil.
方塊或惡魔
Well, let me remind you what you did next…
讓我們回憶一下你那個時候的反應
Incorrect!
錯誤
Shit, you were wrong.
可惡，猜錯了
Don't worry.
現在還不需要擔心
You were so confident.
你非常有自信
Just as if you knew you'd get it right next term.
那表情好像在說 你接下來一定能答對
That convinced me.
這時候我就確信了
You eliminated the possibility of it being diamonds.
你知道答案絕對不是方塊
Meaning the third diamond
也就是說，第三張方塊
must be in your hand.
一定在你手上
Shit, you were wrong.
可惡，猜錯了
So the right answer was devil.
所以答案就是惡魔
He knew what I was thinking.
被他看透了
Everything.
全看透了
You're a smart cookie, a master of logic,
你很聰明，是徹底的理論派
but to gamblers,
但是理論派
masters of logic
對賭徒而言
are worse than fools.
無異於傻瓜
Sitting ducks.
比傻瓜還要傻
This guy is good.
這傢伙好厲害
A master of his craft,
完全被他玩弄於股掌之上
he's got me in the palm of his hand.
這傢伙是個強敵
Time for the second round.
現在開始第二回合
FIVE ONE ROUND TWO
（五印一當，第二回合）
Hey, Ui.
初
Got anything I can write on?
你有書寫用具嗎？
Hold on a sec. What are you two up to?
慢著，你們想玩什麼把戲？
This is a game of probability.
這是一個關乎機率的遊戲
I'm gonna write down the math.
我想記錄和計算一下
Is that allowed?
這樣可以吧？
I'll allow it.
可以
All I have to do
我現在要做的是
is make sure I don't give anything away.
不給那個傢伙透露任何線索
To do that…
為了達到這個目的
Awaken the devil power.
我要啟動惡魔之力…
LIMITED PERFECT
（有限完美）
I'll use my devil power to stick the cards together, hiding the symbols.
我要用“凍結一分鐘” 把花色重疊並凍結在一起
I'm showing three cards.
我要亮三張牌
The problem is whether this counts as showing cards.
問題是，這樣是否還算是亮牌
Now you receive three new cards.
那麼我再發三張牌給你
Yes, he let it go.
很好，他認可了
Why are they stuck together?
這些牌怎麼黏在一起了？
Could it be…
難道這個是…
this is your devil power?
你的惡魔之力？
Who knows?
這可不好說
Gado, my guess is spades.
卡多，我的答案是黑桃
Incorrect.
錯誤
The second player is Senya Uesugi.
接下來回答的是上杉潛夜
Do you wish to show any cards?
你打算亮牌嗎？
It's a shit hand, so be my guest.
手氣好差，我全都亮出來
You receive three new cards.
那麼我重新發三張牌給你
Say, Terurin.
小照照
You seem to be trying your best to keep me in the dark this time,
雖然你這一回合 很努力不透露任何線索給我
but you've given something big away.
但很遺憾，你還是給了我重大的線索
The cards you fixed with the devil power
你用惡魔之力凍結的牌
are all clubs, right?
全是梅花，對吧？
-How the hell? -Ui.
-你怎麼知道？ -初…
Look at that.
不會吧？
Did I guess right?
真被我猜中了？
You can only use a devil power once,
惡魔之力在遊戲中只能用一次
so the best time to use it,
最好的使用時機
would be when you have a really good hand.
就是你手握三張好牌的時候
Like when you have three of the same card.
比如你的三張牌 都是同一個花色的時候
You made a crucial mistake.
你犯了一個關鍵錯誤
Do you know what it was?
你自己發現了嗎？
What are you talking about?
什麼錯誤？
When you took the new cards,
你拿到新發的三張牌時
you turned the middle one the other way up.
你將中間的牌顛倒了一下
The other two symbols must be upside down,
反過來說，另外兩張牌
but that doesn't seem to bother you, does it?
就算顛倒了也沒差，對吧？
The cards on each side
所以旁邊的兩張牌
must be diamonds?
一定是方塊？
Right.
說得沒錯
Including the cards in my hand,
再結合我手上的牌
now I know 11 cards out of 15.
在15張牌中 我已經知道了11張牌的花色
Spades were already guessed incorrectly,
而黑桃是錯誤答案
so that means,
所以
it's a devil card.
答案是惡魔
Incorrect.
錯誤
Not three clubs?
不是三張方塊？
But you gave it away.
但你明明露餡了
Oh, sorry. Teruasa asked me to play along.
那個啊 那是我按照朝的指示演給你看的
ACT LIKE HE'S RIGHT
（如果潛夜猜這三張牌）
IF HE GUESSES WHAT THE THREE CARDS ARE
（不管他怎麼猜 都做出被猜中的反應）
Teruasa had him fooled from the start.
他從一開始就在騙這個傢伙
Since you narrowed it down to a devil card,
多虧你剛才猜了“惡魔”
now I know you have two hearts in your hand.
現在我知道你手上有兩個紅心
Therefore,
因此
the answer is diamond.
答案是方塊
Correct.
正確
Teruasa Oda wins one point.
織田照朝得一分
Crap, I think I'm falling for him.
完蛋了，我好像喜歡上織田照朝了
So…
那麼…
Shall we continue the game of deception you love so much?
我們還要繼續玩 你最喜歡的詐欺遊戲嗎？
I'm suddenly starting to enjoy myself.
我突然覺得這場遊戲變有趣了呢
Teruasa and Ui?
照朝君和初君？
I think they're playing Senya Uesugi to win back the company.
我猜他們為了將公司贏回來 正在跟上杉潛夜對戰
Yuki, Yuki!
悠季…
I got some new info on Senya Uesugi.
我收集到了有關上杉潛夜的新情報
New info?
新情報？
FIVE ONE ROUND THREE
（五印一當，第三回合）
Yukari, will you get my bag?
小紫，可以幫我把包包拿過來嗎？
-Here. -Thanks.
-給你 -謝謝
Gado-chin, can I take a memo too?
卡多哥，我也可以做筆記吧？
Yes, I'll allow it.
可以，我同意
Perfect.
太好了
Thanks to Terurin's little notepad trick,
託小照照的福
I can use mine without anyone blinking an eye.
我可以光明正大用我的筆了
If I mark the cards like this,
我如果像這樣標記紙牌
I'll know what's in his hand.
就能知道他手上拿著什麼牌
Isn't this a cute game,
這樣玩不是很有趣嗎？
Terurin?
小照照
Three cards.
我亮三張牌
You receive three new cards.
那麼我再發三張牌給你
That's a pretty bad hand.
手氣好差啊
As long as I mark one more card, I'm good.
我只要再標記一張牌就行了
Your father was killed by Hoshin.
小照照，你爸爸是被崩心殺死的吧？
When did you decide to get revenge?
你是什麼時候決定要復仇的？
Ever since he died 13 years ago.
從他在13年前死去的時候
Seriously? You really know how to hold a grudge!
真的嗎？竟然這麼執著
That's enough.
你不要說了
You can't understand how someone feels after losing their family like that.
照朝突然間失去了親人 這種感受你根本無法理解
You're right, I don't get it.
對，我無法理解
This idiot could not get any worse.
這傢伙太讓人不爽了
Senya Uesugi, what's your answer?
上杉潛夜，說出你的答案
-Hearts. -Incorrect.
-紅心 -錯誤
He's getting sloppy.
這傢伙好隨便啊
By the way, Terurin.
對了，小照照
What would you do if you saw an old man
如果你看到一個老人提著沉重的包袱
walking along with heavy bags?
在路上走，你會怎麼做？
I'd see if he needed help.
我會問他是否需要幫助
Impressive.
真了不起
Instead of an old man, what if it was a child?
如果那個人不是老人，而是小孩呢？
The same thing.
一樣
Is that compassion?
這是同情嗎？
You feel pity for those in trouble?
你對受難的人感到同情？
It may appear so.
換個角度來看，也許是的
So what if it was a 14-year-old middle school student?
如果那個人是個14歲的初中生呢？
What if that student believed he had caused his father's death,
如果那個初中生認為 父親的死是自己造成的
and instead of bags,
而他揹負的不是包袱
he was carrying a heavy burden of guilt?
而是沉重的罪惡感，你會怎麼做？
I owe thanks to your son, who's been digging around online.
我得感謝你的兒子 他一直在網路上調查
His research led me right to you.
正因他的調查，才讓我找到了你
Okamoto!
岡本
Chairman Oda!
會長
Dad! Dad!
爸爸
What are you trying to say?
你想說什麼？
"Responsibility" sure sounds fancy.
“責任”這個詞說起來好聽
But are you living your own life?
但你能說你這是在過自己的生活嗎？
Teruasa Oda?
織田照朝君？
Don't let him get to you, Teruasa.
不要被他挑釁，照朝
I'm showing three cards.
我要亮三張牌
You receive three new cards.
那麼我再發三張牌給你
You've started doing it too.
看來你也開始這樣做了
Too?
“也”？
No.
莫非他…
Where is it? Where?
在哪裡？在哪裡呢？
The spade has one dot.
這張黑桃牌上有一個點
The club has four dots.
梅花牌上有四個點
The devil card has five dots.
惡魔牌上有五個點
He marked them.
他標記了
Finally realized?
終於發現了？
I marked them too.
我也在做標記
In the second round.
在第二回合的時候
Impossible.
不可能
The answer
答案是
is clubs.
梅花
Correct.
正確
Teruasa Oda gains one point.
織田照朝得一分
Yes.
太好了
You've got this.
得分了，照朝
Incredible.
厲害啊
That was incredible, Terurin!
真厲害，小照照
I owe thanks to the gods for meeting you. Wait!
感謝神讓我遇見了你，不
I owe thanks to the devil.
要感謝惡魔才對
But you're the only one I can't lose to.
但是我唯獨不能輸給你
What do you mean?
什麼意思？
I'll tell you if you win.
你贏了我就告訴你
But that'll never happen.
但你不可能會贏的
Ten years ago, when Senya Uesugi was a high school student,
十年前，當上杉潛夜還是高中生時
he came home late at night after hanging out with a friend.
有一天他和朋友出去玩 到深夜才回家
ELDEST SON FIRST TO DISCOVER THE INCIDENT
（長子首先發現慘案）
AND REPORT IT TO THE POLICE
（並報了警）
He saw his parents and younger sister
他親眼看到爸媽和妹妹
get attacked and murdered by a robber.
被強匪襲擊並殺害
MURDERER STILL ON THE RUN
（凶手仍在逃）
How awful.
真可怕
And the robber?
那個強匪呢？
He was caught half a year later.
他在事發半年後被抓
But it wasn't the police who found him.
但逮到他的不是警察
It was Senya Uesugi himself.
而是上杉潛夜自己
He caught him alone?
他一個人逮到了犯人？
As the only survivor, he felt responsible,
作為唯一的倖存者 他感到自己責任重大
and went behind the police to catch the killer.
於是決心不靠警察，自己抓到犯人
He went through something similar to Teruasa.
他的經歷和照朝君有些相似
Maybe
那個人說不定
he's not just after the keys.
不僅僅是為了得到鑰匙
You're the best.
你最棒了
This is fun.
真有意思
I wish we could play forever.
真想一直跟小照照玩啊
FIVE ONE ROUND FOUR
（五印一當，第四回合）
I'm showing two cards.
我亮兩張牌
Are you kidding me?
還能這樣？
He's totally scribbled over them.
他把花色完全塗黑了
It's just one cool move after the next with you.
你真能接二連三地耍花招
Gotcha. Both cards are marked.
被我發現了，兩張牌都被標記了
Did you spot it?
你看到啦？
Teruasa Oda, it's your turn to guess.
織田照朝，說出你的答案
Hearts.
紅心
Incorrect.
錯誤
Senya Uesugi, you go second.
上杉潛夜，接下來換你
How many cards do you want to show?
你要亮幾張牌？
All three.
三張全亮
Just copying now?
有樣學樣？
I was thinking of doing it before you.
其實我剛才也想這麼做
Promise.
真的
It doesn't matter. It's two diamonds and a spade.
沒關係 這三張牌是兩個方塊和一個黑桃
Two clubs
兩張梅花
and a devil card.
和一張惡魔
Now you're just giving it away?
現在你把線索都說出來了？
You marked all three anyway.
這三張都被你做了標記
No point hiding them.
藏著也沒有意義了
By the way, I know what's in your hand.
對了，你手上的牌是
A heart, diamond, and a club.
紅心、方塊和梅花
Don't expect me to tell you if you're right or wrong.
不管你猜對與否，我什麼都不會說的
Do what you want.
隨你
Then why don't we take a peek
你幫這些牌都做了標記
at the back of these cards.
我們來看看這兩張牌的背面
Both cards have five dots.
兩張牌都有五個點
So it must be two devil cards, right?
所以這兩張牌肯定都是惡魔，對吧？
If that's right, the answer is
如果是這樣，那麼答案是
spade?
黑桃？
No,
不
wrong.
不對
Teruasa put fake markings on those cards.
照朝在那兩張牌上做了假標記
They're actually spades.
它們實際上是黑桃
So the answer is devil.
所以答案是惡魔
Senya Uesugi.
上杉潛夜
Wait!
等等
What now?
怎樣？
I was about to say it's not spades.
我本來想說不是黑桃
I spoke just in time, didn't I?
現在還來得及吧？
Make your mind up!
回答時要給出確切的答案
Sorry.
不好意思
Something pretty caught my eye.
我剛剛一瞥，發現了好東西
I found your…
我發現了…
second markings.
你的二次標記
On the key.
就在鑰匙圖案上
Terurin put a mark in black pen on the black section.
你用黑筆在黑色區域做了標記
You can see which card it is
在光線的反射下
by the way it catches the light.
你能辨別你標記的是什麼牌，對吧？
He spotted it.
他發現了
The black card
我的答案是
is a devil card.
惡魔
Correct. One point to Senya Uesugi.
正確，上杉潛夜得一分
Take that!
帥啦
Two points each!
兩人各得兩分
You are a master of suspicion.
在懷疑人方面，你真是個天才
The next round will decide the game.
下一回合將決定遊戲的勝負
I'm looking forward to the greatest thrill of my life.
希望能體會到無與倫比的刺激
FIVE ONE ROUND FIVE
（五印一當，第五回合）
From the marking, I know one of the cards is a heart.
根據所做的標記 我知道有一張牌是紅心
The other two
其餘兩張
have had their markings covered up.
它們的標記完全被塗掉了
Senya Uesugi goes first.
上杉潛夜先來
Do you wish to show any cards?
你要亮牌嗎？
I'll show two.
我亮兩張
The symbols are covered up.
花色被塗黑了
Which cards are they?
它們是什麼牌呢？
Two of the new cards
這兩張新牌
don't have a single mark made by me or Senya.
沒有我或上杉做的標記
There can only be two cards like that.
只有兩張牌沒被做過標記
They must be hearts.
那兩張牌的花色一定是紅心
That makes three hearts in total.
三張紅心都被你抽中了嗎？
Don't let him get away with it.
別讓他猜出來
Might as well use my secret weapon, "Senya-kun Eye."
看來該使用我的祕密武器 “潛夜君之眼”了
Let me explain what it is.
我來解釋一下“潛夜君之眼”是什麼
It's a devil power that lets me look through obstacles to see what I want.
這個惡魔之力 能讓我穿過障礙看到我想看的內容
Look through obstacles?
穿過障礙？
I can see a club and two diamonds.
我能看到一張梅花和兩張方塊
So the answer is
所以答案是
spade.
黑桃
Incorrect.
錯誤
What? You're lying!
開什麼玩笑？
It makes perfect sense.
我的解題流程沒問題呀
Teruasa Oda, you go second.
織田照朝，接下來輪到你了
Do you wish to show cards?
你要亮牌嗎？
All three.
三張全亮
This card must be a diamond.
這張被塗黑的牌一定是方塊
Teruasa Oda, your answer.
織田照朝，說出你的答案
In total, I know what nine of the cards are.
我一共認出了九張牌
Spades has been ruled out
黑桃被排除了
so it must be a devil card, or clubs.
所以答案一定是惡魔或梅花
He must have been bluffing about the devil power.
那傢伙說的惡魔之力一定是唬人的
If he'd seen the card, he'd have got it right.
如果他真能看到 那他剛才肯定能答對
Come on, we don't have all day.
還沒想好嗎？太陽要下山了
But why would he lie?
但是他為什麼要撒這種謊？
Did he do it to divert my attention away from something else?
他是想轉移我的注意力 讓我忽視某些細節嗎？
The two cards he revealed at the start…
他在一開始亮出的兩張牌…
Could they have more markings on them?
上面會不會還有其他標記？
Gado-chin, shouldn't he get a yellow card?
卡多哥，是不是該罰他一張黃牌？
STEAL THE RABBIT
（把兔子包包搶過來）
Fine.
我知道了
Have some Mog chocolate for the wait.
等待時吃塊莫格巧克力吧
-Hey! -Here.
照朝
Thank you.
謝謝
I win.
我贏了
You can't win if you don't guess.
你還沒說答案，怎麼可能會贏？
A magician whose tricks are this transparent,
魔術師的把戲被識破了
ought to hang up their hat.
你還是金盆洗手吧
What's he planning to do?
你打算怎麼處理最早亮出的兩張牌？
A club and a devil card.
是梅花和惡魔
It's invisible ink.
這是隱形墨水
It can only be seen with a black light.
只有用黑光照射，文字才會顯現
I was right behind him and even I didn't notice.
我就站在他身後，竟然沒發現
So, Teruasa Oda,
那麼織田照朝
what is your answer?
說出你的答案
The cards you were hiding were a club and devil.
你塗抹的牌是梅花和惡魔
-Wait… -The answer is…
-喂，小照照… -答案是…
Clubs.
梅花
Teruasa Oda,
織田照朝
incorrect!
錯誤
It can't be.
錯誤？
Just like I thought!
果然如我所料，小照照
I knew you'd figure out my trick.
我就知道你會識破我的障眼法
This is the pen.
這支筆
On the other side,
它的另一頭
it really is invisible ink.
確實是隱形墨水
But, hey.
但是呢
Your discovery was all part of my
讓你發現它，其實是我設計好的…
strategy.
計謀
Just as you guessed, Senya-kun Eye was a bluff.
和你猜的一樣 “潛夜君之眼”是唬你的
I used a little something called
為了引你上鉤，我用上了一點
acting.
演技
I put on quite a show to lure you in.
我演得很厲害吧？
Now for the big reveal.
這兩張牌的真正花色是…
Two clubs.
兩個梅花
You were completely fooled.
你中了我的計
You figured out my special trick, but I still managed to deceive you.
你識破了我的特殊能力是假的 但我還是騙過了你
I'm having too much fun, Terurin.
我玩得好開心，小照照
Senya Uesugi, what is your answer?
那麼上杉潛夜，說出你的答案
This is…
我的答案是
a devil card.
惡魔
Correct.
正確
One point to Senya Uesugi.
上杉潛夜得一分
Bringing him up to three points,
由於他首先獲得三分
the winner of Five One,
所以“五印一當”的贏家是
is Senya Uesugi!
上杉潛夜
How wonderful it feels!
好開心啊
Terurin…
小照照
You were the best opponent ever.
你是一流的對手
Teruasa.
照朝
Teruasa Oda,
織田照朝
that was short but sweet.
雖然時間很短暫，但我看得很盡興
This brings the game Five One to an end!
“五印一當”到此結束
There's a debt to be paid!
償還賭債
Teruasa! Ui!
照朝君，初君
Teruasa.
照朝君
A debt to be paid.
償還賭債
Cough up.
拿來吧
You can thank me.
你得感謝我
I've freed you from the heavy shackles of responsibility.
是我把你從沉重的“責任”枷鎖中 解救了出來
Teruasa lost.
照朝輸了
Well,
那麼
tell me all you know about the keys.
跟我說說關於惡魔鑰匙的情報吧
From my research,
根據我的調查
the devil's keys have been around since BC.
惡魔鑰匙在公元前就存在了
And have been the cause of much conflict.
它們引發了許多紛爭
There are 99 keys in total.
世界上總共有99把惡魔鑰匙
If you collect them all,
如果能集齊這些鑰匙
you can have the world.
你就能主宰整個世界
On each key,
在每一把鑰匙上
there is a number inscribed that looks like some kind of code.
都刻著一個類似暗號的編碼
That's all I know.
我知道的就這些
Okay, next. I have three favors.
好，接下來你要答應我做三件事
I can ask for anything I want.
不論我提什麼要求都不能拒絕
Please, anything but someone's life.
求求你，不要做傷及性命的事
Give me your hand.
握手
Turn around.
轉圈
Good boy.
好乖
As for my final request,
最後一個要求
I'll save it until later for fun.
等我以後想玩的時候再提
Ten keys in total.
這樣我就有十把鑰匙了
Yukari, wanna play?
小紫，要玩遊戲嗎？
What?
人呢？
Now I kinda understand how to use the keys.
現在我大概瞭解鑰匙的用法了
I just need to find a sucker to play with.
接下來我要找個新手玩遊戲
#selfie #ponytailgirl #mysteriouskey #iwanttostealkeys
（#自拍，#馬尾女孩 #神祕鑰匙，#我要去偷鑰匙）
Can I say－
我說…
Will you…
那把鑰匙…
give the key back to Teruasa?
能不能還給照朝君？
Why, exactly?
為什麼？
Teruasa really needs that key
為了抓住殺父仇人
to catch who killed his father.
照朝君需要這把鑰匙
I don't know.
這個我倒不知道呢
You're the same.
你和他一樣
Your family was attacked and killed too.
你的家人也被襲擊和殺害了
You were just a high school student,
那時你還是一個高中生
but you caught the attacker yourself and turned him into the police.
但你自己抓到了凶手 並把他交給了警方
Could it be that you challenged Teruasa to a game
你之所以想跟照朝君交手
because you were intrigued by how similar you are?
或許是因為 你對經歷相似的他很感興趣，對嗎？
That's kinda messed up if it's true.
如果是這樣，那也太病態了
We can't begin to imagine what they've been through.
我們無法想像他們經歷了多少痛苦
You did your research, huh?
你調查得真仔細啊
Honestly,
說實話
when I look at Terurin,
當我看到小照照時
it reminds me my painful past.
總會想起痛苦的過去
It makes my heart ache.
這讓我很心痛
It's been so difficult.
真令人難受
I wonder if the devil's key…
我在想惡魔鑰匙…
doesn't just bring good luck,
不僅僅能帶來好運
but also brings similar people together.
還能讓相似的人聚在一起
Uesugi…
上杉君
It's all bullshit.
滿嘴謊言
It's all too touching to be genuine.
這傢伙不是這麼真誠的人
He may have been Mr. Nice Guy in the past, but now,
以前他也許是這樣的人，但現在
all he wants is a cheap thrill.
他只是一個 想尋求刺激的“刺激癮君子”
You got me.
被你看出來啦？
You bastard.
你這王八蛋
Why don't you give up all this boring revenge shit?
小照照，復仇這麼無聊 你別再執著了
If what you said is true,
如果你說的是真的
Hoshin is collecting 99 keys,
崩心正在收集99把鑰匙
and seriously trying to take over the world.
想要主宰這個世界
A crazy guy like that.
那麼瘋狂的傢伙
You really wanna take him on?
你真的想跟他作對嗎？
How about
不如
we make a bet on the key?
我們拿惡魔鑰匙賭一把？
With that key, I can challenge Hoshin to a game,
有了那把鑰匙，我就能跟崩心對戰
unearth all the keys and destroy them.
然後找出所有鑰匙並將它們摧毀
I will crush Hoshin's ambitions.
我會摧毀崩心的野心
That's how you'll take revenge?
這就是你的復仇計畫？
Exactly.
沒錯
I'll fight and crush those swallowed by desire,
我會和那些被欲望吞噬的人戰鬥
and set them free.
然後解救他們
They'll probably kill you first.
你可能會在成功之前就被殺掉
But…
但是…
wouldn't that be the best thrill of your life?
對你來說 這不正是最極致的刺激嗎？
How about it?
怎麼樣？
Take the bet.
跟我打賭吧
Join me in my plan,
加入我的計畫，去體驗刺激吧
and I'll make sure it's worth it.
你一定能享受最驚險刺激的時刻
Must be a bit lonely collecting keys by yourself.
你自己一個人收集鑰匙也沒意思
Team up with me.
跟我合作吧
Team up with me, take the keys and destroy them all.
跟我合作，找到鑰匙 然後把它們都摧毀
I'll make your life worth living!
我會讓你的人生變得驚險有趣
Fine.
成交
Glad to have you on board, Senya.
請多指教，潛夜
Can't wait, Terurin.
請多指教，小照照
First of all, let me tell you about Hoshin's organization.
首先我跟你介紹崩心組織的情況
Armed groups have crossed
南美的武裝組織
the South American border in a military incursion.
越過國界發動了軍事襲擊
Thanks to the key.
多虧了惡魔鑰匙
To see our whole plan through…
為了實現我們的計畫
We need to find all 99 keys.
我們要集齊99把鑰匙
Gungnir.
永恆之槍？
NEXT EPISODE
（下集預告）
Whatever danger awaits…
無論前方有什麼危險…
TERUASA VS A GUNGNIR DELEGATE
（照朝對上永恆之槍使者）
…I will crush Gungnir's ambitions.
…我都會摧毀永恆之槍的企圖
A fight for one hundred gold coins.
（百金爭奪）
Cut the crap.
少廢話
It's over.
結束了
I've won.
我贏了